Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/alicaschmalenberg (LinkedIn)

Top-Kenntnisse

Social Media Kommunikation Teamwork

Languages

Englisch (Full Professional)
Italienisch (Limited Working)
Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Mediator: Coach for Communications- and Conflict Training

Honors-Awards

30under30 - Top PR Talents Germany 2019

Alica Schmalenberg

Corporate Communications | 30u30 2019 @PRReport Düsseldorf

Zusammenfassung

Communications & PR Manager savvy in internal, external and executive communications. Worked as project/team/people lead inhouse as well as on agency sides for international companies, incl. DAX40. Skills include: strategic & change communications, content management, project management, staff engagement, brand & culture building, content creation, copywriting, social media.

A course in communications- and conflict training inspired me to study International Communications (B.A.) and Political Communications (M.A.). For my studies I spent five years abroad.

Since 2019 I am part of 30u30 of PR Report: https://bit.ly/3qyR2MF In 2021 I joined GWPR: https://globalwpr.de/

If you have a question or want to connect on all things communications, just drop me a message

Berufserfahrung

PVH Corp.

Corporate Communications Specialist
Juni 2021 - Present (10 Monate)

Düsseldorf, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

TWT Interactive GmbH
Projektmanager
Januar 2021 - Juni 2021 (6 Monate)
Düsseldorf, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

Managed projects in three distinctive areas: Campaigns (e.g. launch campaign for a new app for mobility services), data & analytics (e.g. advising on a data strategy, setting up a new KPI framework) and web development. Coordinating interdisciplinary project teams, managing time and costs as well as advising clients were my daily responsibilities to ensure the successful realization of projects.

JP KOM GmbH

4 Jahre 4 Monate

Group Head & Consultant
Januar 2019 - Januar 2021 (2 Jahre 1 Monat)

Düsseldorf und Umgebung, Deutschland

Junior Consultant

Januar 2018 - Dezember 2018 (1 Jahr)

Düsseldorf, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

Trainee

Oktober 2016 - Dezember 2017 (1 Jahr 3 Monate)

Düsseldorf, Nordrhein-Westfalen, Deutschland

Nebelung Kommunikation GmbH

Strategic & Crisis Communications

August 2014 - August 2015 (1 Jahr 1 Monat)

Hamburg

Consulting and supporting corporations, nonprofit organizations, government agencies and mid-sized companies in resolving conflicts and minimizing public damage.

Hill+Knowlton Strategies

Public Affairs & Corporate Communications

Februar 2014 - Mai 2014 (4 Monate)

Berlin und Umgebung, Deutschland

Next to a three months fulltime internship I wrote my Bachelor's Thesis at Hill+Knowlton. I primarily worked for two clients in the oil & gas sector and analyzed political and economic hot topics.

TBWA\Group Vietnam

Public Relations

Februar 2013 - August 2013 (7 Monate)

Ho Chi Minh City

Ausbildung

Cardiff University / Prifysgol Caerdydd

Master of Arts (MA), Political Communication · (2015 - 2016)

Hanzehogeschool Groningen

Bachelor of Arts - BA, International Communications · (2010 - 2014)

Edinburgh Napier University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Erasmus semester with courses in Social Marketing, Communications Management and Italian \cdot (2012 - 2013)